export default {

  difficulty1: [
    {
      question: 'Space travelers from the United States are called astronauts.\nFrom Russia, they’re called cosmonauts. Where are taikonauts from?',
      response1: 'Japan',
      response2: 'China',
      response3: 'England',
      response4: 'Korea',
      correctAnswer: '2',
      time: '15',
      difficulty: '1',
    },

    {
      question: 'Who painted the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?',
      response1: 'Leonardo da Vinci',
      response2: 'Michelangelo',
      response3: 'Rembrandt',
      response4: 'Claude Monet',
      correctAnswer: '2',
      time: '10',
      difficulty: '1',
    },

    {
      question: 'In what year did the Titanic sink?',
      response1: '1910',
      response2: '1913',
      response3: '1911',
      response4: '1912',
      correctAnswer: '4',
      time: '10',
      difficulty: '1',
    },

    {
      question: 'The Nobel Prize is one of the most prestigious awards in the field of science.\nThe man behind the award –Alfred Nobel– invented what?',
      response1: 'Telephone',
      response2: 'Dynamite',
      response3: 'Internet',
      response4: 'Light bulb',
      correctAnswer: '2',
      time: '20',
      difficulty: '1',
    },

    {
      question: 'The name of this disease stems from the medieval term that means ‘bad air’.\nWhat disease is it?',
      response1: 'Malaria',
      response2: 'Flu',
      response3: 'Black death',
      response4: 'COVID',
      correctAnswer: '1',
      time: '20',
      difficulty: '1',
    },
  ],

  difficulty2: [
    {
      question: 'Who was the scientist to propose the three laws of motion?',
      response1: 'Albert Einstein',
      response2: 'Nikola Tesla',
      response3: 'Isaac Newton',
      response4: 'Galileo Galilei',
      correctAnswer: '3',
      time: '15',
      difficulty: '2',
    },

    {
      question: 'This man is responsible for reshaping the way early man believed the solar system worked.\nHe proposed that the Earth was not the center of the universe,\nand that the sun was instead at the center of our solar system. Who was he?',
      response1: 'Copernicus',
      response2: 'Galileo Galilei',
      response3: 'Archimedes',
      response4: 'Aristotle',
      correctAnswer: '1',
      time: '25',
      difficulty: '2',
    },

    {
      question: 'In what year was Alaska sold to the United States of America?',
      response1: '1876',
      response2: '1877',
      response3: '1865',
      response4: '1867',
      correctAnswer: '4',
      time: '15',
      difficulty: '2',
    },

    {
      question: 'Joseph Henry was given credit for this invention in 1831.\nWhich was said to revolutionize the way that people communicate during the time.\nWhat was his invention?',
      response1: 'The telephone',
      response2: 'The television',
      response3: 'The Internet',
      response4: 'The telegraph',
      correctAnswer: '4',
      time: '25',
      difficulty: '2',
    },

    {
      question: 'New York City was originally known by which Dutch name?',
      response1: 'Nieuw Lelystad',
      response2: 'Nieuw Amsterdam',
      response3: 'Nieuw Maastricht',
      response4: 'Nieuw Haarlem',
      correctAnswer: '2',
      time: '15',
      difficulty: '2',
    },
  ],

  difficulty3: [
    {
      question: 'In 1953, the United States of America conducted its first and only nuclear artillery test.\nWhere was the test held?',
      response1: 'Alaska',
      response2: 'Nevada',
      response3: 'Arizona',
      response4: 'Louisiana',
      correctAnswer: '2',
      time: '25',
      difficulty: '3',
    },

    {
      question: 'Who was the first US President to declare war?',
      response1: 'James Madison',
      response2: 'Bill Clinton',
      response3: 'Ronald Reagan',
      response4: 'James Monroe',
      correctAnswer: '1',
      time: '15',
      difficulty: '3',
    },

    {
      question: 'The evacuation of more than 300,000 trapped Allied troops,\nby military and civilian ships, was completed on June 4, 1940, during World War II."\nWhere did this evacuation take place?',
      response1: 'Brighton, England',
      response2: 'Dunkirk, France',
      response3: 'Normandy, France',
      response4: 'London. England',
      correctAnswer: '2',
      time: '20',
      difficulty: '3',
    },

    {
      question: 'On June 1, 1794, the Battle of the First of June was fought in the\nAtlantic Ocean between France and which other country?',
      response1: 'Great Britain',
      response2: 'Spain',
      response3: 'Netherlands',
      response4: 'United States',
      correctAnswer: '1',
      time: '20',
      difficulty: '3',
    },

    {
      question: 'Which Japanese company, now one of the largest automobile manufacturers in the world,\nbecame an independent company on August 28, 1937?',
      response1: 'Mitsubishi',
      response2: 'Honda',
      response3: 'Subaru',
      response4: 'Toyota',
      correctAnswer: '4',
      time: '20',
      difficulty: '3',
    },
  ],
};
